# **Rohil Prajapati**

Samakhusi, Kathmandu, Nepal | M: 9860687243 <u>rohilprajapati@gmail.com</u>

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rohilprajapati/

### **Summary**

Currently a Back-end Developer have experienced in designing and developing API, with a solid foundation in programming languages such as Python, JavaScript. I have successfully delivered project in healthcare domain. With 1+ year of experience in back-end/system application development in Python (Django).

### **Experience**

#### Back-end Developer Starter Nepal Pvt. Ltd.

Aug 2022 - Jun 2023

- Designing and Developing back-end API with Framework like Django, DRF.
- Implementing JSON Web Tokens (JWT) for authentication.
- Analyzing the data and generating report according to requirement.
- Collaborate and communicate with the front-end developers to create the back-end according to the requirement.
- Perform R & D to use the best cutting-edge technologies to meet the business goals.

Internship Trainee

Jul 2020 - Apr 2021

Starter Nepal Pvt. Ltd.

#### Education

Bachelor in Computer Application	Aug 2019 - Apr 2024
Tribhuwan University, Kathmandu, Nepal	

School Leaving Certificate (S.L.C.) (+2)

Jul 2019

National Examinations Board

Grade: 2.81

Secondary Education Examination (S.E.E)

Jun 2017

National Examinations Board

Grade: 3.55

#### Skills

- Python(Django, Flask)
- REST API
- MySQL/PostgreSQL Database
- Linux
- Postman

- Web Development
- JavaScript
- PHP
- Git
- Quasar.js

# **Projects Exposure**

# **Building Hospital Management System**

May 2023

Starter Nepal Pvt. Ltd.

**Objective:** This project was initiate to handle the pharmacy, hospital service billing, Report generation of the billing and Lab report Management System

**Description:** Currently this system have record of selling 12000+ quantity of medicine worth NRs. 600k + Monthly billing. This system was build-using Django, Quasar (Vue.js). My role in this project was to design and develop the API for this system. Setup JWT authentication to the project. Testing API using Postman.

Demo Site Link: <a href="https://hmsdemo.starternepal.com/">https://hmsdemo.starternepal.com/</a>

Username: admin Password: admin

### **E-commerce Web Application**

Aug 2022

**Asian College of Higher Studies** 

**Objective:** This Project was initiate to allow user to buy and sell clothing product online and admin to monitor the user, products stock manage the application.

**Description:** Project was create to meet the requirement of Bachelor Projects program in 4<sup>th</sup> semester. The core feature of the project are **Online Payment Gateway Integration (eSewa)**, Admin Panel to monitor and manage the stock, manage users, etc.

Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/RohilPrajapati/Wosa-Pasa">https://github.com/RohilPrajapati/Wosa-Pasa</a>

# **Quiz Web Application**

Apr 2022

**Asian College of Higher Studies** 

**Objective:** This project was initiate to make user play the quiz game in the form of web Application.

**Description:** Project was create to meet the requirement of Scripting Language Subject in 4<sup>th</sup> Semester. It allows user to play quiz game and admin Panel to monitor user result and manage user.

Github Link: https://github.com/RohilPrajapati/Quizer

#### Reference:

Bishnu Maharjan
DevOps Engineer at Genius Systems
(Mentor)

Mobile No.: 9849160769

Sabin Raghubanshi
Django Developer at Starter Nepal
(Supervisor)

Mobile No.: 9851140541